<?xml-model href="nightvale_structure.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="specConstrain.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<episode id="pilot">
    <segment type="intro" voice="cecil">A friendly desert community where the sun is hot, the moon is beautiful,
        and mysterious lights pass overhead while we all pretend to sleep. Welcome to Night
        Vale.</segment>

    <segment type="news" voice="cecil">Hello, listeners. To start things off, I’ve been asked to read this
        brief notice: <ref type="group" spec="cityCouncil">The City Council</ref> announces the opening of <ref type="place" spec="dogPark">a new Dog Park</ref> at <ref type="place" spec="address">the corner of Earl
        and Somerset</ref>, near <ref type="place" spec="ralphs">the Ralph’s</ref>. They would like to remind everyone that <ref type="nonperson" spec="dog">dogs</ref> are not allowed
        in the Dog Park. People are not allowed in the Dog Park. It is possible you will see <ref type="group" spec="hoodedFigure">Hooded
            Figures</ref> in the Dog Park. Do not approach them. Do not approach the Dog Park. The fence is
        electrified and highly dangerous. Try not to look at the Dog Park, and especially do not
        look for any period of time at the Hooded Figures. The Dog Park will not harm you. </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil">And now, the news. <ref type="person" spec="josie">Old Woman Josie, out near the Car Lot</ref>, says <ref type="group" spec="angels">the Angels</ref>
        revealed themselves to her. Said they were ten feet tall, radiant, and one of them was
        black. Said they helped her with various household chores. One of them changed a light bulb
        for her — the porch light. She’s offering to sell the old light bulb, which has been touched
        by an Angel. It was the black Angel, if that sweetens the pot for anyone. If you’re
        interested, contact Old Woman Josie. She’s out near the <ref type="place" spec="carLot">Car Lot</ref>. </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil"><ref type="person" spec="carlos">A new man</ref> came into town today. Who is he? What does he want from us?
        Why <ref type="object" spec="carlosHair">his perfect and beautiful haircut</ref>? Why <ref type="object" spec="carlosLabcoat">his perfect and beautiful coat</ref>? He says he is a
        scientist. Well…<ref type="abstract" spec="science">we have all been scientists at one point or another in our lives</ref>. But why
        now? Why here? And just what does he plan to do with <ref type="object" spec="sciEquip">all those breakers and humming
        electrical instruments</ref> in <ref type="place" spec="lab">that lab he’s renting</ref> — the one next to <ref type="place" spec="bigRicos">Big Rico’s Pizza</ref>? No one
        does a slice like Big Rico. No one. </segment>
    <segment type="psa" voice="cecil">Just a reminder to all the parents out there: let’s talk about safety when taking your
        <ref type="group" spec="children">children</ref> out to play in <ref type="place" spec="sandWastes">the scrublands and the sand wastes</ref>. You need to <ref type="abstract" spec="health">give them plenty of
        water</ref>, make sure there’s <ref type="group" spec="tree">a shade tree</ref> in the area, and keep an eye on the <ref type="object" spec="helicopter">helicopter colors</ref>.
        Are the unmarked helicopters circling the area black? Probably <ref type="group" spec="worldGovt">World Government</ref>. Not a good
        area for play that day. Are they blue? That’s <ref type="group" spec="secPol">the Sheriff’s Secret Police</ref>. They’ll keep a
        good eye on your kids, and hardly ever take one. Are they <ref type="abstract" spec="art">painted with complex murals</ref>
        depicting <ref type="nonperson" spec="bird">birds of prey</ref> diving? <ref type="group" spec="mysteryHelicopter">No one knows</ref> what those helicopters are, or what they want.
        Do not play in the area. Return to <ref type="place" spec="home">your home</ref> and lock the doors until a Sheriff’s Secret
        Policeman leaves <ref type="object" spec="flower">a carnation</ref> on your porch to indicate that the danger has passed. Cover
        your ears to blot out the screams. Also remember: <ref type="culture" spec="gatorade">Gatorade</ref> is basically soda, so <ref type="abstract" spec="health">give your
        kids plain old water and maybe some orange slices when they play</ref>.</segment>

    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="object" spec="plane">A commercial airliner</ref> flying through local airspace disappeared today, only to reappear
        in the <ref type="place" spec="elementary">Night Vale Elementary</ref> gymnasium during <ref type="abstract" spec="sports">basketball practice</ref>, disrupting practice quite
        badly. The jet roared through the small gym for only a fraction of a second. And before it
        could strike any players or structure, it vanished again. This time, apparently, for good.
        There is no word yet on if or how this will affect Night Vale Mountain Lions’ game schedule,
        and also if this could perhaps be the work of their bitter rivals the Desert Bluffs Cacti.
        <ref type="place" spec="desertBluffs">Desert Bluffs</ref> is always trying to show us up through fancier uniforms, better pre-game
        snacks, and possibly by transporting a commercial jet into our gymnasium, delaying practice
        for several minutes at least. For shame, Desert Bluffs. For shame.</segment>

    <segment type="main" voice="cecil"><ref type="person" spec="carlos">That new scientist</ref> — who we now know is named Carlos — called a town meeting. <ref type="object" spec="carlosFace">He has a
        square jaw, and teeth like a military cemetery</ref>. <ref type="object" spec="carlosHair">His hair is perfect, and we all hate, and
        despair, and love that perfect hair in equal measure</ref>. <ref type="person" spec="josie">Old Woman Josie</ref> brought <ref type="object" spec="bread">corn muffins</ref>
        which were decent, but lacked <ref type="object" spec="salt">salt</ref>. She said <ref type="group" spec="angels">the Angels</ref> had taken her salt for a Godly
        mission, and she hadn’t yet gotten around to buying more. <ref type="abstract" spec="science">Carlos told us that we are by far
        the most scientifically interesting community in the U.S., and he had come to study just
        what is going on around here.</ref> He grinned, and everything about him was perfect, <ref type="abstract" spec="love">and I fell
            in love instantly</ref>. <ref type="group" spec="worldGovt">Government agents from a Vague, Yet Menacing Agency</ref> were in the back,
        watching. I fear for Carlos. I fear for Night Vale. I fear for anyone caught between what
        they know and what they don’t yet know that they don’t know. </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil">We received a press release this morning. The <ref type="group" spec="businessAssoc">Night Vale Business Association</ref> is proud
        to announce the opening of <ref type="place" spec="waterfront">the brand new Night Vale Harbor and Waterfront Recreation Area</ref>. I
        have been to these facilities myself recently on their invitation, and I can tell you that
        it is absolutely top of the line and beautiful. Sturdy docking areas made from eco-friendly
        post-consumer material, a boardwalk for pedestrians, and plenty of stands ready for local
        food vendors and merchants to turn into a bustling public marketplace. Now, there is some
        concern about the fact that, given we are in the middle of a desert, there is no actual
        water at the waterfront. And that is a definite drawback, I agree. For instance, the
        boardwalk is currently overlooking sagebrush and rocks. The Business Association did not
        provide any specific remedies for this problem, but they assured me that the new harbor
        would be a big boost to Night Vale nonetheless. Maybe wait until a flash flood and head down
        there for the full waterfront experience.</segment>

    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="group" spec="nra">The local chapter of the NRA</ref> is selling bumper stickers as part of their fund-raising
        week. They sent the station one to get some publicity. And we’re here to serve the
        community, so I’m happy to let you all know about it. The stickers are made from good,
        sturdy vinyl, and they read: Guns don’t kill people. It’s impossible to be killed by a gun.
        We are all invincible to bullets and it’s a miracle. Stand outside of your front door and
        shout “NRA!” to order one.</segment>

    <segment type="main" voice="cecil"><ref type="person" spec="carlos">Carlos</ref> and <ref type="group" spec="scienceTeam">his team of scientists</ref> warn that <ref type="place" spec="phantomHouse">one of the houses</ref> in the new development of
        Desert Creek, out back of the elementary school, doesn’t actually exist. "It seems like it
        exists," explained Carlos and <ref type="object" spec="carlosHair">his perfect hair</ref>. "Like it’s just right there when you look at
        it. And it’s between two other identical houses, so it would make more sense for it to be
        there than not." But, he says, <ref type="abstract" spec="science">they have done experiments</ref> and the house is definitely not
        there. At news time, the scientists are standing in a group on the sidewalk in front of the
        nonexistent house, daring each other to go knock on the door. </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil">A great howling was heard from the <ref type="place" spec="postOffice">Night Vale Post Office</ref> yesterday. Postal workers
        claim no knowledge, although passers-by describe the sound as being a little like a human
        soul being destroyed through black magic. <ref type="person" spec="apacheTracker">The Indian tracker</ref> — now, I don’t know if you’ve
        seen this guy around. He’s the one that appears to be of maybe Slavic origin, yet wears an
        Indian headdress out of some racist cartoon and claims to be able to read tracks on asphalt.
        He appeared on the scene, and swore that he would discover the truth. No one responded
        because it’s really hard to take him seriously in that headdress of his.</segment>

    <segment type="advert" voice="cecil"><ref type="nonperson" spec="arbysLights">Lights</ref>. Seen in the sky above the <ref type="culture" spec="arbys">Arby</ref>’s. Not the glowing sign of Arby’s. Something
        higher, and beyond that. We know the difference. We’ve caught on to their game. We
        understand the “lights above Arby’s” game. Invaders from another world. Ladies and
        gentlemen, the future is here, and it’s about 100 feet above the Arby’s.</segment>

    <segment type="main" voice="cecil"><ref type="person" spec="carlos">Carlos</ref> and <ref type="group" spec="scienceTeam">his scientists</ref> at <ref type="place" spec="quakeStation">the monitoring station</ref> near <ref type="place" spec="rte800">Route 800</ref> say their seismic
        monitors have been indicating <ref type="abstract" spec="earthquake">wild seismic shifts</ref> — meaning to say that the ground should be
        going up and down all over the place. I don’t know about you folks, but the ground has been
        as still as the crust of a tiny globe rocketing through <ref type="abstract" spec="void">an endless void</ref> could be. Carlos
        says that they’ve double-checked the monitors and they are in perfect working order. To put
        it plainly, there appears to be catastrophic earthquakes happening right here in Night Vale
        that absolutely no one can feel. Well, submit an <ref type="abstract" spec="insurance">insurance claim</ref> anyway. See what you can
        get, right?</segment>

    <segment type="traffic" voice="cecil">Traffic time, listeners. Now, <ref type="group" spec="secPol">police</ref> are issuing warnings about <ref type="object" spec="ghostCar">ghost cars</ref> out on the
        highways, those cars only visible in the distance reaching unimaginable speeds leaving
        destinations unknown for destinations more unknown. They would like to remind you that you
        should not set your speed by these apparitions, and doing so will not be considered
        “following the flow of traffic.” However, they do say that it’s probably safe to match speed
        with <ref type="nonperson" spec="arbysLights">the mysterious lights in the sky</ref>, as whatever entities or organizations responsible
        appear to be cautious and reasonable drivers. </segment>
    <segment type="weather" voice="weather">And now, the weather. [“These and More Than These" by Joseph Fink] </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">Welcome back, listeners. <ref type="nonperson" spec="sun">The sun</ref> didn’t set at the correct time today, <ref type="person" spec="carlos">Carlos</ref> and <ref type="group" spec="scienceTeam">his
        team of scientists</ref> report. They’re quite certain about it. They checked multiple clocks and
        the sun definitely set ten minutes later than it was supposed to. I asked them if they had
        any explanations but they did not offer anything concrete. Mostly they sat in a circle
        around a desk clock, staring at it, murmuring, and cooing. Still, we must be grateful to
        have the sun at all. It’s easy to forget in this hot, hot, hot desert climate, but things
        would actually be slightly harder for us without the sun. The next time the sun rises,
        whatever time that turns out to be, take a moment to feel grateful for all the warmth and
        light and even, yes, extreme heat that our desert community is gifted with. </segment>
    <segment type="psa" voice="cecil"><ref type="group" spec="cityCouncil">The City Council</ref> would like to remind you about the tiered Heavens, and the hierarchy
        of <ref type="group" spec="angels">Angels</ref>. The reminder is that you should not know anything about this. The structure of
        Heaven and the organizational chart are privileged information, known only to the City
        Council members on a need-to-know basis. Please do not speak to or acknowledge any Angels
        that you may come across while shopping at <ref type="place" spec="ralphs">the Ralph’s</ref> or at <ref type="place" spec="bowlingAlley">the Desert Flower Bowling Alley
        and Arcade Fun Complex</ref>. They only tell lies and do not exist. Report all Angel sightings to
        the City Council for treatment. </segment>
    <segment type="psa" voice="cecil">And now a brief public service announcement. <ref type="nonperson" spec="reptile">Alligators</ref>: can they kill your children?
        Yes. Along those lines, to get personal for a moment, I think the best way to die would be
        swallowed by a giant snake. Going feet-first and whole into a slimy maw would give your life
        perfect symmetry. </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil">Speaking of <ref type="place" spec="bowlingAlley">the Desert Flower Bowling Alley
        and Arcade Fun Complex</ref>, its owner, <ref type="person" spec="teddyWilliams">Teddy
        Williams</ref>, reports that he has found the entrance to <ref type="place" spec="tinyCity">a vast underground city in the pin
        retrieval area of Lane 5</ref>. He said he has not yet ventured into it; merely peered down at its
        strange spires and broad avenues. He also reports voices of <ref type="group" spec="tinyPeople">a distant crowd</ref> in the depths of
        that subterranean metropolis. Apparently the entrance was discovered when a bowling ball
        accidentally rolled into it, clattering down to the city below with sounds that echoed for
        miles across the impossibly huge cavern. So, you know, whatever population that city has,
        they know about us now, and we might be hearing from them very soon. </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil"><ref type="person" spec="carlos">Carlos, perfect and beautiful</ref>, came into our studios during the break earlier but
        declined to stay for an interview. He had some <ref type="object" spec="sciEquip">sort of blinking box</ref> in his hand covered with
        wires and tubes. Said he was <ref type="abstract" spec="science">testing the place for "materials."</ref> I don’t know what materials
        he meant but that box sure whistled and beeped a lot. When he put it close to the microphone
        it sounded like, well, <ref type="nonperson" spec="bird">like a bunch of baby birds had just woken up</ref>. Really went crazy.
        Carlos looked nervous. I’ve never seen that kind of look on someone with <ref type="object" spec="carlosFace">that strong of a
        jaw</ref>. He left in a hurry. Told us to evacuate the building. But then, who would be here to
        talk to sweetly to all of you out there? </segment>
    <segment type="closing" voice="cecil"><ref type="abstract" spec="weather">Settling in to be another clear night and pretty evening here in Night Vale.</ref> <ref type="abstract" spec="love">I hope all
        of you out there have someone to sleep through it with.</ref> Or, at least, good memories of when
        you did. Goodnight, listeners. Goodnight. </segment>
    <segment type="proverb" voice="credits">Today’s proverb: Look to the north. Keep looking.
        There’s nothing coming from the south. </segment>
</episode>
