<?xml-model href="nightvale_structure.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="specConstrain.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<episode num="2" title="glowCloud" airdate="2012-07-01">
    <segment type="intro" voice="cecil">The desert seems vast, even endless, and yet scientists tell us that somewhere, even
        now, there is snow. Welcome to Night Vale.</segment>

    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="group" spec="tourismBoard">The Night Vale Tourism Board</ref>’s <ref type="abstract" spec="visitable">“Visit-able Night Vale” campaign</ref> has kicked off with
        posters encouraging folks to take their family on a scenery-filled jaunt through the trails
        of <ref type="place" spec="radonCanyon">Radon Canyon</ref>. Their slogan? “The view is literally breathtaking.” Posters will be placed
        at police stations and frozen yogurt shops in nearby towns, along with promotional giveaways
        of plastic sheeting and re-breathers. </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">And now, the news. Have any of our listeners seen <ref type="nonperson" spec="glowCloud">the glowing cloud</ref> that has been
        moving in from the west? Well, <ref type="person" spec="johnPeters">John Peters — you know, the farmer</ref>? He saw it over the
        western ridge this morning. Said he would have thought it was <ref type="nonperson" spec="sun">the setting sun</ref> if it wasn’t
        for the time of day. Apparently the cloud glows in a variety of colors, perhaps changing
        from observer to observer, although all report a low whistling when it draws near. <ref type="abstract" spec="death">One death</ref>
        has already been attributed to the Glow Cloud. But listen, it’s probably nothing. If we had
        to shut down the town for every mysterious event that at least one death could be attributed
        to, we’d never have time to do anything, right? That’s what the <ref type="group" spec="secPol">Sheriff’s Secret Police</ref> are
        saying, and I agree. Although, I would not go so far as to endorse their suggestion to run
        directly at the cloud, shrieking and waving your arms, just to see what it does. </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="person" spec="apacheTracker">The Apache Tracker</ref>, and I remind you that this is that white guy who wears the huge and
        cartoonishly inaccurate Indian headdress, has announced that he has found some disturbing
        evidence concerning the recent incident at <ref type="place" spec="postOffice">the Night Vale Post Office</ref>, which has been sealed
        by <ref type="group" spec="cityCouncil">the City Council</ref> since the great screaming that was heard from it a few weeks ago. He
        said that using ancient Indian magics, he slipped through council security into the post
        office, and observed that all the letters and packages had been thrown about as in a
        whirlwind. That there was the heavy stench of scorched flesh. That the words written in
        blood on the wall said, “More to come, and soon.” Can you believe this guy said he used
        Indian magics? What an asshole! </segment>
    <segment type="personal" voice="cecil">Here’s something odd: there is <ref type="nonperson" spec="khoshekh">a cat</ref> hovering in the men’s bathroom at the radio
        station here. He seems perfectly happy and healthy, but it’s floating about four feet off
        the ground next to the sink. Doesn’t seem to be able to move from its current hover-spot. If
        you pet him, he purrs, and he’ll rub on your body like a normal cat if you get close enough.
        Fortunately, because he’s right by the sink, it was pretty easy to leave some water and food
        where he could get it, and it’s nice to have a station pet. Wish it wasn’t trapped in a
        hovering prison in the men’s bathroom, but listen: no pet is perfect. It becomes perfect
        when you learn to accept it for what it is. </segment>
    <segment type="advert" voice="cecil">And now a message from our sponsors. I took a walk on the cool sand dunes, brittle
        grass overgrown, and above me in <ref type="abstract" spec="void">the night sky</ref> above me I saw. Bitter taste of unripe
        peaches and a smell I could not place nor could I escape. I remembered other times that I
        could not escape. I remembered other smells. The moon slunk like a wounded animal. The world
        spun like it had lost control. Concentrate only on breathing, and let go of ideas you had
        about nutrition and alarm clocks. I took a walk on the cool sand dunes, brittle grass
        overgrown, and above me in the night sky above me I saw. This message was brought to you by
        <ref type="culture" spec="cocaCola">Coca Cola</ref>. </segment>
    <segment type="psa" voice="cecil"><ref type="group" spec="cityCouncil">The City Council</ref>, in cooperation with <ref type="group" spec="worldGovt">government agents from a vague yet menacing
        agency</ref>, is asking all citizens to stop by <ref type="place" spec="elementary">the Night Vale Elementary School gymnasium</ref> tonight
        at 7:00 for a brief questionnaire about mysterious sights that definitely no one saw and
        strange thoughts that in no way occurred to anyone. Because all of us are normal, and to be
        otherwise would make us outcasts from our own community. Remember: if you see something, say
        nothing. And drink to forget. </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="group" spec="boyScouts">The Boy Scouts of Night Vale</ref> have announced some slight changes to their hierarchy,
        which will now be the following: Cub Scout, Boy Scout, Eagle Scout, Blood Pact Scout, Weird
        Scout, Dreadnought Scout, Dark Scout, Fear Scout, and finally, Eternal Scout. As always,
        signup is automatic and random, so please keep an eye out for the scarlet envelope that will
        let you know <ref type="group" spec="children">your son</ref> has been chosen for the process. </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">This is probably nothing listeners, but <ref type="person" spec="johnPeters">John Peters — you know, the farmer</ref> — he reports
        that <ref type="nonperson" spec="glowCloud">the Glow Cloud</ref> is directly over <ref type="place" spec="oldTown">Old Town Night Vale</ref>, and appears to be raining small
        creatures upon the earth. Armadillos, <ref type="nonperson" spec="reptile">lizards</ref>, <ref type="nonperson" spec="bird">a few crows</ref>, that kind of thing. Fortunately,
        the animals appear to be dead already, so <ref type="group" spec="animalControl">the Night Vale Animal Control Department</ref> has said
        that it should be a snap to clean those up. They just have to be tossed on <ref type="object" spec="animalPyre">the eternal
        animal pyre</ref> in <ref type="place" spec="grovePark">Mission Grove Park</ref>, so, if that’s the worst the Glow Cloud has for us, I say
        go ahead and do your daily errands. Just bring along <ref type="object" spec="umbrella">a good strong umbrella</ref> capable of
        handling falling animals up to, say, ten pounds. More on the Glow Cloud as it continues to
        crawl across our sky. And hey, here’s a tip, take <ref type="group" spec="children">your kids</ref> out and use the Cloud’s
        constantly mutating hue to teach him or her the names of colors. It’s fun, and it shows them
        <ref type="abstract" spec="education">the real-life applications of learning</ref>. </segment>
    <segment type="psa" voice="cecil">Alert: <ref type="group" spec="secPol">the Sheriff’s Secret Police</ref> are searching for a fugitive named <ref type="person" spec="hiram">Hiram McDaniels</ref>,
        who escaped custody last night following a 9:00 PM arrest. McDaniels is described as a
        five-headed dragon, approximately 18 feet tall, with mostly green eyes, and weighing about
        3600 pounds. He is suspected of insurance fraud. McDaniels was pulled over for speeding last
        night, and the Secret Police became suspicious when he allegedly gave the officers a fake
        driver’s license for <ref type="person" spec="frankChen">a five foot eight man named Frank Chen</ref>. After discerning that Frank
        Chen was actually a five-headed dragon from somewhere other than our little world, the
        Secret Police searched McDaniels’ vehicle. Representatives from local civil rights
        organizations have protested that officers had no legal grounds to search the vehicle, but
        they ceded the point when reminded by Secret Police officials that our backwards court
        system will uphold any old authoritarian rule made up on the fly by unsupervised
        gun-carrying thugs of <ref type="group" spec="cityCouncil">a shadow government</ref>. The Secret Police say McDaniels escaped custody
        by breathing fire from his purple head, and he was last seen flying and shrieking over <ref type="place" spec="redMesa">Red
        Mesa</ref>. Secret Police are asking for tips leading to the arrest of Hiram McDaniels. They
        remind you that, if seen, he should not be approached, as he is literally a five headed
        dragon. Contact the Sheriff’s Secret Police if you have any information. Ask for Officer
        Ben. Helpful tipsters will earn one stamp on their <ref type="object" spec="alertCitizenCard">Alert Citizen card</ref>. Collect five stamps,
        and you get stop sign immunity for one year. </segment>
    <segment type="calendar" voice="cecil">And now, a look at the community calendar. Saturday, <ref type="place" spec="library">the Public Library</ref> will be
        unknowable. Citizens will forget the existence of the library from 6:00 AM Saturday morning
        until 11:00 PM that night. The library will be under a sort of renovation. It is not
        important what kind of renovation. Sunday is Dot Day. Remember, red dots on what you love,
        blue dots on what you don’t. Mixing those up can cause permanent consequences. Monday, <ref type="person" spec="louieBlasco">Louie
        Blasco</ref> is offering bluegrass lessons in the back of <ref type="place" spec="musicShop">Louie’s Music Shop</ref>. Of course, the shop
        burned down years ago, and Louie skipped town immediately after with his insurance money,
        but he’s sent word that you should bring your instrument to the crumbled ashy shell of where
        his shop once was, and pretend that he is there in the darkness teaching you. The price is
        $50 per lesson, payable in advance. Tuesday afternoon, join <ref type="group" spec="pta">the Night Vale PTA</ref> for a bake
        sale to support <ref type="abstract" spec="war">Citizens For a Blood Space War</ref>. Proceeds will go to support neutron bomb
        development and deployment to our outer solar system allies. Wednesday has been canceled due
        to a scheduling error. And on Thursday is a free concert. And…that’s all it says here. </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">New call in from <ref type="person" spec="johnPeters">John Peters — you know, the farmer?</ref> Seems <ref type="nonperson" spec="glowCloud">the Glow Cloud</ref> has doubled
        in size, enveloping all of Night Vale in its weird light and humming song. <ref type="abstract" spec="sports">Little League</ref>
        administration has announced that they will be going ahead with the game, although there
        will be an awning built over the field due to the increase in size of the animal corpses
        being dropped. I’ve had multiple reports that <ref type="nonperson" spec="lion">a lion</ref>, like the kind you would see on the
        sun-baked plains of <ref type="place" spec="africa">Africa</ref>, or a pee-stained enclosure at a local zoo, fell on top of the
        <ref type="place" spec="iceCreamShop">White Sand Ice Cream Shop</ref>. The shop is offering <ref type="object" spec="iceCream">a free dipped cone </ref>to anyone who can figure
        out how to get the thing off. <ref type="group" spec="secPol">The Sheriff’s Secret Police</ref> have apparently taken to shouting
        questions at the Glow Cloud, trying to ascertain what exactly it wants. So far, the Glow
        Cloud has not answered. The Glow Cloud does not need to converse with us. It does not feel
        as we tiny humans feel. It has no need for thoughts or feelings of love. The Glow Cloud
        simply is. All hail the mighty Glow Cloud! All hail! </segment>
    <segment type="weather" voice="cecil">And now, slaves of the Cloud, the weather. [“The Bus is Late" by Satellite High]</segment>

    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">Sorry, listeners. Not sure what happened in that earlier section of the broadcast — as
        in I actually don’t remember what happened. Tried to play back the tapes, but they’re all
        blank, and smell faintly of <ref type="object" spec="vanilla">vanilla</ref>. <ref type="nonperson" spec="glowCloud">The Glow Cloud</ref>, meanwhile, has moved on. It is now just
        a glowing spot in the distance, humming east to destinations unknown. We may never fully
        understand, or understand at all what it was and why it dumped a lot of dead animals on our
        community. But, and I’m going to get a little personal here, that’s the essence of life,
        isn’t it? Sometimes you go through things that seem huge at the time, like a mysterious
        glowing cloud devouring your entire community. While they’re happening they feel like the
        only thing that matters, and you can hardly imagine that there’s a world out there that
        might have anything else going on. And then the Glow Cloud moves on. And you move on. And
        the event is behind you. And you may find that, as time passes, you remember it less and
        less. Or absolutely not at all, in my case. And you are left with nothing but a powerful
        wonder at the fleeting nature of even the most important things in life — and the faint but
        pretty smell of vanilla. </segment>
    <segment type="closing" voice="cecil">Dear listeners, here is a list of things. Emotions you don’t understand upon viewing a
        <ref type="nonperson" spec="sun">sunset</ref>. Lost pets, found. Lost pets, unfound. A secret lost pet city on the moon. <ref type="group" spec="tree">Trees</ref> that
        see. Restaurants that hear. <ref type="abstract" spec="void">A void</ref> that thinks. A face half-seen just before falling asleep.
        Trembling hands reaching for desperately needed items. Sandwiches. Silence when there should
        be noise. Noise when there should be silence. Nothing when you want something. Something
        when you thought there was nothing. Clear plastic binder sheets. Scented dryer sheets. Rain
        coming down in sheets. Night. Rest. Sleep. End. Goodnight, listeners. Goodnight. </segment>
    <segment type="proverb" voice="credits">Today’s proverb: Men are from Mars; women are from Venus; Earth is a hallucination;
        podcasts are dreams.</segment>
</episode>
