<?xml-model href="nightvale_structure.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<?xml-model href="specConstrain.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<episode id="stationManagement">
    <segment type="intro" voice="cecil">The arctic is lit by the midnight sun. The surface of the
        moon is lit by the face of the earth. Our little town is lit, too, by <ref type="nonperson" spec="arbysLights">lights just above that
        we cannot explain</ref>. Welcome to Night Vale.</segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="object" spec="newspaper">The Night Vale Daily Journal</ref> has announced that they will be
        cutting back their publication schedule to Monday through Thursday only, due to the economic
        downturn and a massive decline in the literate population. The Thursday Daily Journal will
        now be called the Weekend Edition, and on Sundays, newspaper kiosks — usually filled with
        important newsprint — will be filled with <ref type="object" spec="milk">2% milk</ref>. When asked “Why milk?,” <ref type="person" spec="leanneHart">the Journal’s
        publishing editor Leanne Heart</ref> said, “It is important that we maintain an unbiased approach
        to news reporting.” </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="group" spec="businessAssoc">The Night Vale Business Association</ref> is proud to announce the
        new <ref type="place" spec="stadium">Night Vale Stadium</ref>, next to <ref type="place" spec="waterfront">the Night Vale Harbor and Waterfront Recreation Area</ref>. The
        stadium will be able to seat 50,000 but will be closed all nights of the year except
        November 10th, for the annual <ref type="abstract" spec="hoodedFigureParade">Parade of the Mysterious Hooded Figures</ref>, in which all of our
        favorite ominous <ref type="group" spec="hoodedFigure">Hooded Figures</ref> — the one that lurks under the slide in the <ref type="place" spec="elementary">Night Vale
        Elementary</ref> playground, the ones that meet regularly in <ref type="place" spec="dogPark">the Dog Park</ref>, and the one that will
        occasionally openly steal babies (and for a reason no one can understand, we all stand by
        and let him do it) — all of them will be parading proudly through Night Vale Stadium. I tell
        you, with these new facilities, it promises to be quite a spectacle. And then it promises to
        be a vast, dark, and echo-y space for the other meaningless 364 days of the year. </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">Here at the radio station it’s contract negotiation season
        with <ref type="nonperson" spec="stationManagement">the station management</ref> again! That’s always an interesting time. Now, obviously, I’m
        not allowed to go into details, but negotiation is tricky when you’re never allowed to
        glimpse what you’re negotiating with. Station management stays inside <ref type="place" spec="stationOffice">their office</ref> at all
        times, only communicating with us through <ref type="object" spec="envelope">sealed envelopes</ref> that are spat out from under the
        door like a sunflower shell through <ref type="object" spec="teeth">teeth</ref>. Then, in order to respond, you just kind of shout
        at the closed door and hope that management hears. Sometimes you can see movements through
        the frosted glass, large shapes shifting around, strange tendrils whipping through the air.
        Architecturally speaking, the apparent size of management’s office does not physically make
        sense given the size of the building, but it’s hard to say, really, as no one has ever seen
        the actual office — only its translucence. Look, I’ve probably said too much. I can see down
        the hall that an envelope just came flying out. I pray it’s not another HR retraining
        session in <ref type="place" spec="darkBox">the Dark Box</ref>. Uugh! But what can I say? I’m a reporter at heart. I can’t not
        report. Oh, my… </segment>
    <segment type="calendar" voice="cecil">Let’s go to the seven-day outlook. Your daily shades of
        the sky forecast: Monday: Turquoise. Tuesday: Taupe. Wednesday: Robin’s egg. Thursday:
        Turquoise/taupe; Friday: Coal dust; Saturday: Coal dust with chances of indigo in the late
        afternoon. Sunday: <ref type="abstract" spec="void">Void</ref>.</segment>
    <segment type="psa" voice="cecil"><ref type="group" spec="cityCouncil">The City Council</ref> has asked me to remind everyone about the new
        drive to clean up <ref type="object" spec="trash">litter</ref>. Night Vale is our home. And who wants to leave trash all over
        their home? Put it in the garbage can, listeners! And if you see any trash around, pick it
        up and throw it away. Do your part. Unless the trash is marked with <ref type="object" spec="flag">a small red flag</ref>. The
        Council has asked me to remind you that any litter marked with a red flag is not to be
        picked up or approached. Remember the slogan: “No flag? Goes in the bag. Red flag? Run!” </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil">Listeners, we are currently fielding numerous reports that
        <ref type="object" spec="book">books</ref> have stopped working. It seems that all over Night Vale, books have simply ceased
        functioning. <ref type="group" spec="scienceTeam">The scientists</ref> are studying one of the broken books to see if they can
        understand just what is going on here. The exact problem is currently unclear, but some of
        the words being used include “sparks,” “meat smell,” “biting,” and “lethal gas.” For your
        own safety, please do not attempt to open a book until we have more information on the
        nature and cause of these problems. <ref type="group" spec="cityCouncil">The City Council</ref> has released only a brief statement
        indicating that their stance on books has not changed and that, as always, they believe that
        books are dangerous and inadvisable and should not be kept in private homes. </segment>
    <segment type="psa" voice="cecil">Another warning for Night Vale residents: Sources say that <ref type="place" spec="usedNDiscount">the Used and Discount
        Sporting Goods store</ref> on <ref type="place" spec="address">Flint Drive</ref> is a front for <ref type="group" spec="worldGovt">the World Government</ref>. This is based on
        extensive study of the location, and also because it has a black helicopter pad on which
        <ref type="object" spec="helicopter">black helicopters</ref> regularly depart and land. Fairly unusual for a used and discount sporting
        goods store. We sent <ref type="person" spec="intern">our intern, Chad</ref>, to try buying a tennis racket — and have not heard
        back from him for several weeks. This brings me to a related point: To the parents of Chad
        the Intern: we regret to inform you that your son was lost in the line of community radio
        duty, and that he will be missed and never forgotten. May you all feel blessed to have the
        family that you have, and if you’re looking for sporting goods, check out <ref type="place" spec="playBall">Play Ball</ref> right
        over by our own Night Vale community radio station! Play Ball is only a front for <ref type="group" spec="secPol">the
        Sheriff’s Secret Police</ref>, and so can be completely trusted. </segment>
    <segment type="news" voice="cecil"><ref type="person" spec="larryLeroy">Larry Leroy, out on the edge of town</ref>, reported that <ref type="abstract" spec="creepingFear">a Creeping Fear</ref> came into Night
        Vale today. He felt it first as a mild apprehension, then a growing worry, and finally a
        mortal panic. It passed from him to the employees at <ref type="place" spec="carLot">the Car Lot</ref>, who crouched behind their
        cars and cast fearful eyes at the empty sky. It did not affect <ref type="person" spec="josie">Old Woman Josie</ref>, presumably
        because of <ref type="group" spec="angels">her angelic protection</ref>, but it went from there to the rest of the town until we
        all were shivering in anticipation for a terrible thing we could not yet see. I myself was
        frozen, sure that any movement would lead to death; that any word would be my last. Of
        course, that also could have been the contracts negotiations with <ref type="nonperson" spec="stationManagement">station management</ref>, and
        the hideous envelope I just received. Also, I’m battling <ref type="abstract" spec="lymeDisease">Lyme disease</ref>. Meanwhile, the
        Creeping Fear passed, first leaving Larry Leroy out on the edge of town, and then the Car
        Lot, where they went back to offering gently used cars at affordable prices, and finally the
        rest of us — who could go back to living with the knowledge that at any given moment we will
        either live or die, and it’s no use guessing which. It is not currently known where the
        Creeping Fear will go next — hopefully to <ref type="place" spec="desertBluffs">Desert Bluffs</ref>. It would serve them right. </segment>
    <segment type="personal" voice="cecil">Two hawk-eyed listeners sent in reports that <ref type="person" spec="carlos">Carlos, our curious scientific visitor</ref>,
        was seen getting <ref type="object" spec="carlosHair">his beautiful, beautiful hair</ref> cut. He was having his gorgeous hair shorn!
        Cut! Cut short! So very short from <ref type="object" spec="carlosFace">his perfectly-shaped brilliant head</ref>! Listeners, I am not
        one to gossip even if it is a local celebrity, but please explain to me why Carlos would
        strip away — decimate! — any part of his thick black hair…not to ignore the dignified, if
        premature, touch of gray in the temples. What treacherous barber should agree to such
        depravity? Who takes mere money, or even soulless joy, in depriving our small community of
        such a simple, but important, act as luridly admiring Carlos’s stunning coif? Reports from
        two intrepid sources are that it was <ref type="person" spec="tellyBarber">Telly the Barber</ref>. Telly, who likes <ref type="abstract" spec="sports">sports</ref> and has
        posters of combs. Telly the Barber seems to be the one who betrayed our community. Telly the
        Barber. It is Telly the Barber at <ref type="place" spec="address">the corner of Southwest 5th Street and Old Musk Road</ref>, with
        the red and white spinning pole and the sign that says, “Telly’s.” Telly is about 5’9” with
        a small mustache and a thick pot belly. He talks with <ref type="language" spec="accent">an accent</ref> and sneers. Telly the Barber
        cut Carlos’s beautiful hair. According to reports. Telly. </segment>
    <segment type="traffic" voice="cecil">Now, while I gather myself, let’s have a look at traffic. Oh, wow! Well, that looks
        pretty good. Yup. Yessss. Okay, not too bad there either I see. Oh! That gentleman needs to
        slow it down! It is not a race my friend! Not a literal one, anyway. That has been traffic. </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">And now for an editorial. I don’t ask favors much, dear listeners, that you know. But
        I’m asking all of you now to conduct <ref type="abstract" spec="writing">a letter-writing campaign</ref> to <ref type="nonperson" spec="stationManagement">station management</ref>, which
        was not…pleased with my discussion of their physical attributes and behavior and is now
        threatening to shut down my show — or possibly my life — for good. Their wording was…kind of
        ambiguous. Obviously we will not be able to deliver the letters directly to the management,
        per se, as no one has ever opened their door; but we can shout the content of the letters
        outside their office and we presume, given an anatomy that includes ears, they will be able
        to hear what you have to say. So if you like this show, and you want to hear more of it,
        then we need to hear from you. Make your voice heard to whatever it is that lies in wait
        behind that darkened office door. </segment>
    <segment type="advert" voice="cecil">Oh! I’m sorry dear listeners. We’ll be back after this word from our sponsors. This
        segment has been brought to us by <ref type="place" spec="bigRicos">Big Rico’s Pizza</ref>. Listeners, we are proud to have Big
        Rico’s as a sponsor of our show. You will not find a better pizza joint in all of Night Vale
        then Big Rico’s. Just the other night, I stopped by Big Rico’s. I was in the mood for a
        delicious pizza slice. And since Big Rico’s is the only pizza place in Night Vale that has
        not burnt to the ground in an unsolved <ref type="abstract" spec="arson">arson</ref> case (and did I mention is also the best pizza
        in town), I ordered a single Rico’s slice with two authentic toppings. And boy, was I
        satisfied. The flavor was scrumptious. The taste was also scrumptious. And it was warm, the
        pizza slice. I have been told that even <ref type="group" spec="hoodedFigure">the Hooded Figures</ref> eat there; the wait staff look
        like they avert their hollow gazes quite a bit. Even the City Council offers its ringing
        endorsement of Big Rico’s. All Night Vale citizens are mandated to eat at Big Rico’s once a
        week. It is a misdemeanor not to. Big Rico’s Pizza. No one does a slice like Big Rico,
        folks! No one. </segment>
    <segment type="weather" voice="weather">And now, sweet, sweet listeners…the weather. [“Bill and Annie" by Chuck Brodsky] </segment>
    <segment type="main" voice="cecil">Hello, radio audience. I come to you live from under my desk, where I dragged <ref type="object" spec="recordingEquip">my
        microphone</ref> and am currently hiding in the fetal position. Did you <ref type="abstract" spec="writing">write letters</ref>? Then you
        should not do this anymore. <ref type="nonperson" spec="stationManagement">Station management</ref> has opened its door for the first time in my
        memory, and is now roaming the building. I don’t know exactly what management looks like, as
        that is when I took cover under my desk and I can only hope that they are not listening to
        what’s going out right now or else I may have sealed my fate. I can hear only a kind of
        clicking footstep, and faint hissing sound like — releasing steam. <ref type="person" spec="intern">An intern</ref> went to see
        what management wanted and has not returned. If you are related to Jerry Hartman, afternoon
        board operator at Night Vale Community Radio, I am sorry to inform you that he is probably
        dead or at least corporeally absorbed into management permanently! Jerry and Chad the
        interns will both be missed, but we will surely see them in the <ref type="abstract" spec="thanksgivingContest">Thanksgiving Day Dead
        Citizens Impersonation Contest</ref>, which this year will be in the employee lounge under <ref type="place" spec="mall">the
        Night Vale Mall</ref> from 11:00 AM to 9:45 PM. There will be a cash bar and two <ref type="culture" spec="twister">Twister boards</ref>. I
        am going to see if I can make a break for the door. </segment>
    <segment type="closing" voice="cecil">If you don’t hear from me again, it has truly been a pleasure. Good night, Night Vale.
        And goodbye! </segment>
    <segment type="proverb" voice="credits">Today’s proverb: There’s a special place in Hell. It’s really hip. Very exclusive.
    </segment>
</episode>